<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hrishi Olickel - A Personal Blog</title>
    <description>Personal Blog and Data Repository - Hrishi Olickel</description>
    <link>http://localhost:3000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:3000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 15:32:48 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 15:32:48 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Intentions and Program Mind-Meld Frustrations</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I learned something today that my brain already knew. Triple-clicking on a text view - on an editor, terminal emulator or random display - selects the line. A double click does whatever, but a triple click always selects a line. I found that out courtesy of Rachel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://rachelbythebay.com/w/&quot;&gt;Rachel By The Bay&lt;/a&gt;, but my first response was - triple clicks! Isn’t that a relic of the past from when Windows XP had that weird setting? Or some holdover from Xerox Parc? Do we triple click anymore? Must be hard!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Turns out we do - or at least I do....</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 06:15:31 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/intentions-and-program-mind-meld-frustrations/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/intentions-and-program-mind-meld-frustrations/</guid>
        
        <category>Python</category>
        
        <category>NodeJS</category>
        
        <category>Nano</category>
        
        <category>EMACS</category>
        
        <category>VIM</category>
        
        
        <category>Rants</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We are moving to Go</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post was inspired by a conversation I had a few days ago, where a friend of mine told me about the recent rewrite their systems were undergoing so they could move from a node backend to Go. I didn’t finish that conversation. I’m going to, but I wanted to think and talk about it first. I didn’t want to really ask what was going on, because I wanted plausible deniability that his case didn’t belong in here (What? No! There’s spousal abuse in other countries, its a real problem, but no one I know does it or I’d have...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:01:06 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/were-moving-to-go/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/were-moving-to-go/</guid>
        
        <category>Go</category>
        
        
        <category>Rants</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Juventus: Glucose worries in Chiang Mai and the beginning of the biggest brownie point scheme ever</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay so this one’s been coming for a while. A LONG while. &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.juventus.app&quot;&gt;Juventus&lt;/a&gt; (finally released, yay! - well sort of) was a project that started over two years ago in college. Like anything, it started with a lot of huge hurdles and big ambition, and as a product built for only one person. Story of everything, I guess - except in this case, the hurdles were overcome but the ambition never fully worked out. Unlike most tech products that start with one customer, it wasn’t me I was building it for - but she’s been a happy user for...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:15:15 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/glucose-monitoring-a-story-of-papers,-reverse-engineering-and-the-last-10/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/glucose-monitoring-a-story-of-papers,-reverse-engineering-and-the-last-10/</guid>
        
        <category>Freestyle Libre</category>
        
        <category>Diabetes</category>
        
        <category>Continuous Glucose Monitoring</category>
        
        <category>Juventus</category>
        
        <category>Ionic</category>
        
        
        <category>Software Builds</category>
        
        <category>Hacks of Life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Debugging Node.js in Production: Anatomy of a bug hunt</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;One of last weekend’s projects was building a messenger bot. I’d tried to build one before, but never really started coding as none of the projects I had in mind really worked well with the format of a chatbot. As with blockchain or any emerging technology, trying to shove a new piece of tech into something when it doesn’t fit isn’t a pleasent experience. So I’d left it for a while, and I had built the backend of some bots recently - &lt;a href=&quot;https://m.me/608739242899742&quot;&gt;Trainify&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://m.me/powerunclesg&quot;&gt;Power Uncle&lt;/a&gt; (both of which I might write about at some point...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 08:21:03 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/debugging-node-in-production-anatomy-of-a-bug-hunt/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/debugging-node-in-production-anatomy-of-a-bug-hunt/</guid>
        
        <category>NodeJS</category>
        
        <category>Debugging</category>
        
        <category>Zork</category>
        
        <category>Trainify</category>
        
        <category>Power Uncle</category>
        
        <category>Bootbot</category>
        
        
        <category>Rants</category>
        
        <category>Tales of Work and Woe</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Beauty to an Artificial Intelligence</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is something that’s been on my mind for a while, and it’s been hard to shake - even in beautiful New Zealand. Thought I’d use some of the New Year’s energy to write it up. It’s a bit long - despite my efforts to get it down to a manageable size, but let’s start somewhere.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-we-think-an-ai-is&quot;&gt;What do we think an AI is?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;There’s a scene in the movie “I, Robot”, inspired by Asimov’s series of the same name, where the titular robot tells the main character that he cannot create a work of art. He does this while...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 05:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/quality-to-an-artificial-intelligence/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/quality-to-an-artificial-intelligence/</guid>
        
        <category>Artificial Intelligence</category>
        
        <category>AI</category>
        
        <category>Singularity</category>
        
        <category>Zen and The Art of Motorcycle Maintenance</category>
        
        
        <category>Rants</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dead Money: The problem at the heart of crypto</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a problem that has been troubling me for a number of years now. The rise of crypto around the world has led to it being hailed as the replacement for centralized banking systems, a new international coin, and monikers far too numerous to mention. And while the community is well aware of and hard at work to solve the scaling, privacy and hype issues surrounding crypto, there is perhaps a separate economic problem that lies at the heart of most currencies. This is the problem of dead money.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;how-it-exists&quot;&gt;How it exists&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Before we begin, let’s consider the...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 05:37:54 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/dead-money-the-problem-at-the-heart-of-crypto/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/dead-money-the-problem-at-the-heart-of-crypto/</guid>
        
        <category>Cryptocurrencies</category>
        
        <category>Ethereum</category>
        
        <category>Fractional Reserve Banking</category>
        
        
        <category>Rants</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Converse: An easy sentiment analysis library for Messenger</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sentiment_analysis&quot;&gt;Sentiment Analysis&lt;/a&gt; has been around for a while. The basic idea revolves around measuring and classifying emotions (often boiled down to a single positive/negative measurement from -1.0 to 1.0) based on lexical analysis. Back a good few years ago, when Facebook and Whatsapp (don’t exactly remember if this was before the merge) made it possible for you to download your text conversations en-masse, I immediately did so and was amazed at the amount of data I had accumulated and the possibilities of extracting insights about my life and the patterns therein. Unfortunately, it ended up as a post-it that...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 01:39:03 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/converse-an-easy-sentiment-analysis-library-for-messenger/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/converse-an-easy-sentiment-analysis-library-for-messenger/</guid>
        
        <category>Pypi</category>
        
        <category>Releases</category>
        
        <category>Converse</category>
        
        <category>Sentiment Analysis</category>
        
        <category>Messenger</category>
        
        <category>Entity Extraction</category>
        
        
        <category>Software Builds</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Development across platforms with Docker</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Containerization has only recently become easy and cheap (in terms of memory, cost and development time) through tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;. This has made orchestrating large microservice and distributed architectures far easier, as well as cutting down development time for building and releasing tools. As we saw in the case of &lt;a href=&quot;https://oyente.github.io/benchmarks/&quot;&gt;Oyente&lt;/a&gt; as well as a few other projects I’ve listed here, releasing complex pieces of software - especially for development and research purposes - has become much easier. Complicated and ever-updating lists of dependencies and kernels and distros can be effectively frozen in place and easily shared as...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 07:55:28 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/making-cross-platform-development-easy-and-hard-with-docker/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/making-cross-platform-development-easy-and-hard-with-docker/</guid>
        
        <category>Docker</category>
        
        <category>Virtualization</category>
        
        <category>Oyente</category>
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>Containers</category>
        
        
        <category>Hacks of Life</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building an Arc Reactor</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Because I thought it’d be cool. I’d been working on building a functional version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chua%27s_circuit&quot;&gt;Chua’s Circuit&lt;/a&gt; as an experiment into generating &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.academia.edu/19947852/Random_Number_Generation_using_Chaotic_Circuits&quot;&gt;randomness from chaotic systems&lt;/a&gt; (hope to write that up sometime), and had some time left over (okay not really) to build a case. Iron Man being one of my all-time comfort movie, it seemed like a good fit.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;step-1-the-model&quot;&gt;Step 1: The Model&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:3000/assets/img/ArcReactor/IMG_8566.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;coil1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;First part involved getting a good model of an arc reactor. I usually prefer &lt;a href=&quot;youmagine.com&quot;&gt;YouMagine&lt;/a&gt; as an Ultimaker user and fan - and the models are...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 09:02:40 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/building-an-arc-reactor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/building-an-arc-reactor/</guid>
        
        <category>Iron Man</category>
        
        <category>Movies</category>
        
        <category>Randomness</category>
        
        <category>Arc Reactor</category>
        
        
        <category>Hardware Builds</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Investing in Crypto: A Personal Guide</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Getting started with an investment into cryptocurrencies is often fraught with difficulty. There are a number of options, and the ever-growing list of currency &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.investopedia.com/terms/c/currencypair.asp&quot;&gt;pairs&lt;/a&gt; and arbitrage opportunities make it complicated for the new user. Here’s a (personal) breakdown on some of the options from beginner to intermediate.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some information: A pair is essentially the smallest market you could find - two assets/currencies listed against each other, where the price provides information about the value of one relative to another. For the purposes of the this article, we will be using pairs and markets as interchangeable. A...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 22:13:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:3000/investing-in-crypto-a-personal-guide/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:3000/investing-in-crypto-a-personal-guide/</guid>
        
        <category>Cryptocurrencies</category>
        
        <category>Investment</category>
        
        
        <category>Guides</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
